Guide to the Rachel Field Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Rachel Field collection
1917-1942
YCAL MSS 509
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.17
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of letters from Rachel Field to Ruth Stanley-Brown Feis and from Field to Prentiss Taylor. Also included in the collection are writings by Field, many with illustrations by Taylor, and original writings and drawings by Taylor.
Field, Rachel, 1894-1942
Taylor, Prentiss, 1907-1991
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Prentiss Taylor, 1953, 1955; and Ruth Stanley-Brown Feis, 1966.
"Three Pills in a Bottle" (box 3) was transferred with George Pierce Baker material from Yale University Department of Drama, date unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Rachel Field, 1894-1942
Rachel Field, American novelist, poet, and author of children's fiction.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of letters from Rachel Field to Ruth Stanley-Brown Feis and from Field to Prentiss Taylor. Also included in the collection are writings by Field, many with illustrations by Taylor, and original writings and drawings by Taylor.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1917-1942. II. Writings and Drawings, 1928-1933.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Children's literature; Drawings (visual works); Field, Rachel, 1894-1942; Feis, Ruth Stanley-Brown, 1892-1981; Taylor, Prentiss, 1907-1991
- Correspondence, 1917-1942; Series I; 0.63; (1.5 boxes)
  - Letters from Field to Ruth Stanley-Brown Feis, 1917 August 16-1942 January 2; 6 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    109 autograph postcards signed with 9 typed letters signed, includes originals and typescript annotated copies made by Feis. Enclosed with letter of 5 August 1923 autograph manuscripts of poem "Islands," with letter of 28 November 1927, autograph manuscripts of poems "For October" and "The Thorn Trees"
  - Letters from Field to Prentiss Taylor, 1927 June 17-1941 December 25; 11 (Box 2)
    69 autograph letters signed, 13 autographed postcards signed, 6 typed letters signed, 14 cards and 1 telegram, includes typewritten annotated copies made by Taylor
- Writings and Drawings, 1928-1933, undated; Series II; 0.54; (1.5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - An Alphabet for Boys and Girls, original manuscript of drawing and poems of p.26-27 by Field, undated (Box 2)
  - "Bird in My Garden," original manuscript of poem by Field, 1929 (Box 2)
    Written on the catalogue of an art exhibition, April 29-May 18, 1929. With manuscript of an untitled 4-line stanza on verso, and an unsigned drawing of trees identified on verso as by Miss Field.
  - "A Birthday Broadside: commemorating September 19, 1929, poems and decorations especially for R. F. by P. T." drawings by Prentiss Taylor (Box 2)
  - "Charleston Cries!: for Rachel 1933 from Prentiss," manuscript with drawings by Taylor (Box 2)
  - Cover and decorations for Robert Louis Stevenson's A Child's Garden of Verses (in the Haldeman-Julius Little Blue Book edition), mounted drawings in text by Taylor, undated (Box 2)
  - "Fear is the Thorn," autograph manuscript of two stanzas by Field, undated (Box 2)
  - "For Rachel's Birthday in 1929" original card with drawings by Taylor (Box 2)
  - "The Nine Days' Queen: An Historical Fantasy in One Act," typewritten copy prepared and illustrated with colored drawings by Prentiss Taylor, and presented to Miss Field, Christmas 1928 (Box 2)
  - "Souvenir of the Parade in Honour of Miss Rachel Field on her birthday, the 19th September 1930" original card with drawings by Taylor (Box 2)
  - Original drawing of two boys with a balloon by Field, undated (Box 2)
  - "Three Pills in a Bottle," (playscript) autograph manuscript and typescript by Field (?), undated (Box 3)